hayden-mcneil.com 2015-12-14

# Privacy Policy

_Effective Date:   November 11, 2015_

We at Hayden-McNeil, LLC ("we" or "HM") respect your concerns about privacy and value the relationship we have with you.  This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we collect on our Web sites, how we may use that information, and with whom we may share it. Our Privacy Notice also describes the measures we take to protect the security of the information.  In addition, we describe the choices you can make about how we use the information you provide to us.  We also tell you how you can reach us to update your contact information, contact us with general questions or comments, inquire about our company and its products and services, or answer any questions you may have about our privacy practices.

Click on one of the links below to jump to the listed section:

## Examination Copies

Instructors may request examination copies of textbooks and some supplements from our Web sites.  Instructors may also request preview access to password-protected areas of our Web sites.  In order to fulfill these requests, we will need to collect information that will allow us to confirm your instructor status.  This may include information such as your name, e-mail address, telephone number, the school at which you teach, your course and the book or product you are using in it.

## Adopting Instructor Support

We offer a number of Web-based products and services to adopting instructors.  A user account is necessary to get support for these products and services.  To create a user account, you will need to enter your name and e-mail address.  You will also need to establish a password of your choosing.  We may require additional information to confirm your status as an adopting instructor, e.g., your school name and location, course information, including the textbook you are using, and a telephone number where we can contact you.  In addition, you may choose to provide optional information (e.g., your areas of interest), which will allow us to serve you better.

## Sweepstakes, Contests and Other Promotions

From time to time we may run sweepstakes, contests or other promotions on our Web sites.  If you choose to participate, we may request your contact and other information in connection with the promotion.

## Surveys and Questionnaires

We may ask visitors to our Web sites to complete online surveys and opinion polls on a variety of topics, such as their activities, attitudes, and interests, and our products and services.  These surveys help us understand the needs of our visitors.

## Chat Rooms, Forums, Blogs and Discussion Groups

We may host chat rooms, forums, blogs and/or discussion groups (including by e-mail, bulletin board, instant messaging or other technologies) on our own or on third-party Web sites.  If you choose to participate in a chat room, forum, blog or discussion group, we may request certain information such as your e-mail address, date of birth, academic status and affiliation, and other pertinent information.  Please be aware that some or all the information you provide (including personally identifiable information such as your name) in connection with a chat room, forum, blog or discussion group may be available to specific groups or to the public generally, depending upon the technologies used.

## "Contact Us" and Technical Support

You may choose to contact us through our Web site.  If you e-mail us comments or questions, we will have your e-mail address, as well as any other information you choose to provide.

## Buying our Products

We sometimes offer our books and other products for sale on-line directly to our customers. In order to make a purchase in this way, you will need to register directly with PayPal, a third-party service provider we use to process the purchase. When you do this, you will be their customer as well as ours, and use of your information by PayPal will be governed by their privacy policy, as well as by ours.

## Cookies

We use cookies on our Web sites (including the companion Web sites for some of our books), to help us administer certain site features (such as the _Comment_ system). Cookies are small text files that Web sites often store on the computer hard drives of visitors to their sites.  A cookie contains a unique code, which is used to recognize a computer when a user of that computer returns to a Web site that was visited previously. The "help" portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new cookie, and how to disable existing cookies.  However, in order to use certain features of our Web sites, users must have the "cookie" function on their browsers enabled.

## Other Passive Collection of Information

When you visit our Web site, your browser automatically sends us certain Internet-related information, such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you're using and your originating domain.

We also use log files to collect certain aggregate information about Web site use, such as how many users visited our site, the average time spent on the site and the pages viewed.  By collecting this information, we learn how best to tailor our Web sites to our visitors.  While we generally examine such information only in the aggregate, such information could be linked back to individual IP addresses.  In addition, if you are a registered user of one of our Web sites, this information will be associated with your user name or id.

Information collected through our Web sites is used in connection with the purpose for which it was submitted (for example, to contact you if you win a sweepstakes or contest, to allow you to participate in a chat room, to contact you with an answer to a question, or to send you information or a product you've requested).

We may also contact you as a user of one of our products to:  ask you to serve as a reviewer; to request an appointment with you at your campus or at a conference to talk about an existing or planned product; and other similar kinds of feedback and discussion.  We may also use the information we collect to send you information or products we think may be of interest to you, and to customize our contacts with you.

Finally, we may use some of the information we collect to analyze Web site use and to do other internal analyses, such as market research, that will allow us to better meet the needs of our customers.

We do not sell, rent, trade or otherwise disclose personal information about our Web site visitors, except as described here.  If we describe more limited sharing practices in connection with your use of a specific product or service anywhere on our Web sites, those more limited practices will apply as to that product or service only. We may share the information you provide with companies that are related to HM through common ownership.  We also share information provided by our Web site visitors with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf.  In addition, we may share information about you with non-affiliated third parties whose products or services may be of interest to you.  These third parties may contact you about their products and services.  We will not share your information with these third parties for their own marketing purposes if you request that we not do so.  We may, however, engage in joint marketing activities, such as contests or promotions, with selected third parties and may share personal information about our Web site visitors with them.  In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law, (ii) in response to legal process, (iii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iv) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity.

We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets.  Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to try to ensure that the transferee uses personal information you have provided through this Web site in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Notice.

We provide links to other Web sites for your convenience.  Also, on occasion, we may provide to a department, program, class or instructor access to a third-party Web site (which may also include access to third-party software). These sites may operate independently from HM, and may not be under our control.  These sites may have their own privacy notices in place, which we strongly suggest you review if you visit any linked Web sites.  We may not be responsible for the content of these sites, any products or services that may be offered through these sites, or the privacy practices of these sites.

We use administrative, technical and physical safeguards to protect information in our possession and control against foreseeable hazards.  Please note, however, that perfect security does not exist on the Internet.

We give you the option of requesting that we not share personal information about you with third parties for marketing use. [Click here](http://www.hmpublishing.com/contact-marketing.html) if you DO NOT want us to share your personal information with third parties for their own marketing use. (Keep in mind, however, that some of these companies may have independently obtained your information, in which case you may continue to receive communications from those companies, unless you opt out directly with them.)

Please be aware that we are able to effectuate an opt-out only for a specific e-mail address, or for a name and address or other identifying information. For example, we are unable to opt out "John Smith" by name alone, because of the large number of persons by that name in our databases. So, if you have more than one e-mail address, if you move or change jobs, or if the information you provide us when opting out doesn't match the information in our databases, your opt out request may not be effectuated properly. If you believe you have opted out, but continue to receive e-mails from us, please contact us by one of the means listed under "How to Contact Us", below, and we will endeavor to resolve the issue.

Changes to this Online Privacy Notice will become effective when those changes are posted to our sites. If we make any material changes to the information practices described in this Online Privacy Notice, we will first provide you with a prominent notice. We will not materially reduce your rights under this Online Privacy Notice without first obtaining your consent. Your continued use of the sites subsequent to any change to this Online Privacy Notice constitutes your acceptance of the change. Please review this statement periodically to ensure you are aware of any changes or updates to this Online Privacy Notice. We indicate the effective date of this Online Privacy Notice (and any updates) at the top of the Notice.

If you would like to update your contact information, click here. If you have any questions about our information practices or our products or services, please contact us by [clicking here](http://www.hmpublishing.com/contact-hayden-mcneil.html) or writing us at:

Hayden-McNeil, LLC  
14903 Pilot Drive  
Plymouth, MI 48170  
Attention:  Communications Manager
